### **Manuel Duarte**

Lynnwood, WA 98087
Phone:425-770-3169
duartemanuel@hotmail.com
http://www.linkedin.com/in/manuelduarte1/

### **Personal Profile:**

U.S. Navy veteran with experience leading personnel, managing projects, and delivering effective results. Three years of ADP experience implementing passwords, user legal policies, and regulations. Experienced troubleshooting satellite communication equipment at NCTAMS LANT in Norfolk Virginia. Continued to expand my skills set through a 10-month course of Python 3 programming language through the University of Washington Certification program. Completed 16 weeks of Cybersecurity Training at Facebook for Veterans.

## Skills and knowledge:

Programming Languages: Python 3 (certified) and Bash, CSS5, HTML5 React, and basic Java programming Cloud technologies: AWS EC2, S3, Route53, AWS Lambda, IAM, CloudWatch, CodeDeploy, and CodeBuild Leadership: Technical Training, public speaking, and technical documentation Hardware: Networking, troubleshooting using the OSI model, laptop repair, hardware and software experience Pen-testing Tools: Parrot OS, Kali OS, Burp, Wires-Shark, Python, Cyphers, Rainbow tables, Hashing, Social Engineering, Metasploit, OWASP, CTF, and Linux command line

#### **Education:**

TLG learning for Big-IP Certification Program: TLG Learning 09/2015-11/2015
Networking Administrator: Seattle Central Community College 03/2012-07/2015
B.S. Computer Information Systems: DeVry University 08/2008-09/2011
Associate of Science: Skagit Valley College, Oak Harbor, WA 02/2005-06/2007
ISC: United States Navy, Chicago, IL 04/2002-11/2002
Cybersecurity and Pen-testing Training for Vets: Facebook, Seattle, WA 08/2019 12/2016

## **Certifications**

- Certified AWS Developer Associate, Linux Academy, 2020-03-10
- ◆ Certified Google Cloud Concepts, Linux Academy, 2020-07-05
- ◆ Linux System Administration, Linux Academy, 2020-10-12
- ◆ Linux Essentials Certification, Linux Academy, 2020-06-10
- ◆ Certified Python 3, University of Washington, 2018-09-07
- MAC OS X troubleshooting, Lynda.com, 2019-05-04
- Pvthon Flask course, Lvnda.com 2019-07-11
- ♦ Web Development Foundations: Full-stack, Lynda.com, 2020-07-2017

### **Experience:**

### Tempered Networks, Seattle, WA. 09/2016 – 04/2018 Manufacturing Engineer/Fulfillment Operations

- Experienced using Jira, Salesforce, and Hudson for version control and ticketing tracking
- Used Microsoft 365, Excel, and PowerPoint for inventory, documentation, and product presentations
- Strong working knowledge of Operating systems such as MAC, Windows, and Linux
- Used Bash and Python to automate routine manual tasks
- Used test automation to manufacture, set up, and configure network security devices
- Set up and configured well over 5000 units of switches and other devices for traffic testing traffic between cellular and non-cellular devices

- Created training documentation and assisted in the onboard of new engineers and sales staff
- Provisioned SSL/TLS certificates to over 2500 units such routers, load balancers and switches, and firmware updates
- Responsible for updating and improving procedural documentation that resulted in saving the company time and less human errors
- Used Jira to keep track of bugs associated with the user interface on 7 different networking security platforms and as a tool to keep track of tickets priority and to resolve issues promptly
- Used Salesforce to keep track of inventory, sales, and orders of thousands of devices worth millions of dollars
- Built and flashed the OS in over 5000 switches hardware used for Network Security devices

### Microsoft, Windows Phone, Redmond, WA. 05/2012 -11/2012 Network Engineer I

- Network Cabling, installation, rewiring, and configuration of LTE telecommunication equipment and wireless technologies
- ♦ Managed IPV4/ IPV6 address using WPOPS, DHCP for 25 lab testers engineers
- Provided network efficiency for over 800 users using Solar Winds tools to test connectivity and signal strength
- Used Active Directory administration and user account management tools to manage over 100 users
- Cabled newly developed labs tested networks with well over 100 servers, layer 2 and 3 switches worth over 20 million dollars
- ◆ Tested Wi-Fi connections using Fluke Wi-Fi testing tool and configuration of Cisco devices
- Used TCP/IP, and applied my networking fundamentals such as the OSI model for troubleshooting over 100 devices

## US Navy, NCTAMS LANT, Norfolk VA. 05/2005 – 07/2008 IT Specialist / Network Engineer

- Handled technical troubleshooting of T1 lines, CWSP, INMARSAT, DSCS, and ATM to ensure communication continuity for carriers and submarines for the entire Pacific Fleet
- Worked as a NOC operator, troubleshooting and connecting Ethernet and telecommunication devices for T1 connections
- Worked with several Networking protocols and network tools such as TCP/IP, OSPF, IGP, EIGP, Routing Tables, Ping, Netstat, tcpdump, and Wireshark. Good understanding of all the layers of the OSI model
- Provided excellent customer service and assistance to military and civilian personnel
- Delivered well organized technical presentations using PowerPoint and Microsoft Word
- Conducted monthly training and presentations of EHF, SHF, VHF communication and encryption equipment for more than 200 people
- Meticulously managed and ran updates and inventory to more than 2500 pieces of highly secured equipment for a 3 year period vital to the commutation of the entire Pacific fleet

# US Navy, ADP VP1 COMMAND, Whidbey Island, WA. 01/2002 - 03/2005 IT Specialist/ System Administrator

- Used Network administration tools such as Active Directory to manage over 400+ computer users and credentials
- Provided technical support to command officers and enlisted personal, such as troubleshooting software and hardware issues of computers and printers
- ◆ Solved problems such as internet connection and configuration problems
- Mapped printers to the network, and added users to NMCI accounts in accordance to the Navy regulations
- Filed records and created new accounts in preparation for overseas deployment for 400+ users
- Conducted training of proper security practices which helped minimized security accidents
- Inventoried equipment used by ADP such as printers, laptops, computers, and software
- Experienced using HTML markup language, CSS, and JavaScript for creation of command website